



Aşağı Öveçler District, Kabil Avenue, 1321st Street, No:1/4, Floor:1, Uğur Apartment, Çankaya/Ankara/Turkey



+90 553 310 90 46



ceyhunemreozturk@hotmail.com



linkedin.com/in/ceyhunemreozturk

Languages

Turkish: Mother Tongue,

English: TOEFL iBT (2022): 104/120,

German: A2

Computer Skills

Windows, Ubuntu; Microsoft Office, Libre Office; Python, Tensorflow, Pytorch, MATLAB, Simulink, C++, C, VHDL, Java, Assembly; LTSpice.

CEYHUN EMRE ÖZTÜRK

Electrical & Electronics Engineer

SUMMARY

An R&D engineer with 7 years' experience in programming languages, who is an expert in machine learning and has taken his bachelor's degree in 2020. Well-versed in various programming languages such as Python and MATLAB. 3 years' experience in defense industry. Open for improvement and systematic.

Year of Birth/Place of Birth

1998/ Aydın, Turkey.

Work Experience

March 2022-Present

Research Engineer • ASELSAN

I am conducting research in Natural Language Processing.

December 2019–February 2022

System Design Engineer • ASELSAN

I made effectiveness analysis of the defense systems and I designed the subsystems of the air defense systems.

June 2019-July 2019

Systems Engineering Intern • ASELSAN

I conducted various tests on military radios at the Avionic Communication Systems Engineering Department.

June 2018-July 2018

Research Intern • TÜBİTAK SAGE

I designed interface modules using VHDL and Verilog HDL such that these modules will be used on a type of FPGA which is connected to a QDR II+ SRAM type and I tested these modules by simulation.

Education

- 2020-Present (Expecting to graduate by June 2023): Bilkent University, Ankara, Turkey.
 M.S. in Electrical and Electronics Engineering (GPA: 3.44/4)
- 2016-2020: Bilkent University, Ankara, Turkey.
 B.S. in Electrical and Electronics Engineering (GPA: 3.55/4)
- 2012-2016: Aydın High School of Science, Aydın, Turkey.

Achievements

- GRE General Test (2019): Qualitative: 169/170, Verbal: 158/170.
- ALES 2019 (Nationwide Academic Personnel and Postgraduate Education Entrance Exam): Ranked 87th in Turkey.
- Comprehensive Scholarship in Bilkent University: I gained this scholarship as a result of my rank in LYS 2016.
- LYS 2016 (Nationwide University Entrance Exam): Ranked 234th in Turkey.
- SBS 2011 (Nationwide High School Entrance Exam): Ranked 1st in Turkey.



Publications

- [1] C. E. Öztürk, E. H. Yılmaz, Ö. Köksal, and A. Koç, "Software Module Classification for Commercial Bug Reports", 11th International Workshop on Computational Intelligence for Multimedia Understanding (IWCIM), 2023.
- [2] C. E. Öztürk, Ö. Köksal, Ş. B. Özçelik and A. Koç, "Prior Case Retrieval for the Court of Cassation of Turkey", 2022 16th International Conference on Signal Image Technology & Internet Based Systems (SITIS), 2022, pp. 539-544, doi: 10.1109/SITIS57111.2022.00087.
- [3] Ö. Köksal and C. E. Öztürk, "A Survey on Machine Learning-based Automated Software Bug Report Classification," 2022 International Symposium on Multidisciplinary Studies and Innovative Technologies (ISMSIT), 2022, pp. 635-640, doi: 10.1109/ISMSIT56059.2022.9932822.
- [4] A. C. Aras, C. E. Öztürk and A. Koç, "Feedforward Neural Network Based Case Prediction in Turkish Higher Courts," 2022 30th Signal Processing and Communications Applications Conference (SIU), 2022, pp. 1-4, doi: 10.1109/SIU55565.2022.9864970.
- [5] C. E. Öztürk, Ş. B. Özçelik and A. Koç, "Predicting Outcomes of the Court of Cassation of Turkey with Recurrent Neural Networks," 2022 30th Signal Processing and Communications Applications Conference (SIU), 2022, pp. 1-4, doi: 10.1109/SIU55565.2022.9864914.
- [6] E. Mumcuoglu, C. E. Öztürk, H. M. Ozaktas and A. Koç, "Natural Language Processing in Law: Prediction of outcomes in the Higher Courts of Turkey", *Information Processing and Management*, vol. 58, No. 5: 102684, 2021.

Publications under Review

- [1] C. E. Öztürk, N. Sevim, and A. Koç, "Recurrent Models for Legal Language Processing", Natural Language Engineering (NLE), Submitted: 2023.
- [2] F. Şahinuç, **C. E. Öztürk**, and A. Koç, "Dynamic Sense-Structured Multimodal Gaussian Word Embeddings", *IEEE/ACM Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems* (TNNLS). Submitted: 2023.
- [3] C. E. Öztürk, Ş. B. Özçelik and A. Koç, "Prior Court Case Retrieval with Sentence Transformers in Turkish Courts", *IEEE/ACM Transactions on Audio Speech and Language Processing (TASLP)*, Submitted: 2022.

Teaching

- 2020-2023: Homework grader of the EEE 391 course (Basics of Signals and Systems) at Bilkent University, Ankara, Turkey.
- 2023 Spring: Homework grader of the EEE 486 course (Natural Language Processing) at Bilkent University, Ankara, Turkey.

Social Activities

- 2017-2020: Member of Bilkent IEEE Student Branch.
- 2017-2018: Events Coordinator of Bilkent Free Software Community (Bilkent GNU).
- 2016-2017: Volunteer at the TDP community of Bilkent University. I gave lectures for free to the students who were going to high school or elementary school or middle school.
- 2013-2016: Licensed table tennis player for Aydın High School of Science.

References

- Dr. Aykut Koç-Professor at Electrical and Electronics Engineering Department of Bilkent University-aykut.koc@bilkent.edu.tr
- Dr. Ömer Köksal-Team Leader at ASELSAN-koksal@aselsan.com.tr



- Dr. Kenan Ahıska-Team Leader at ASELSAN-kahiska@aselsan.com.tr
- Talha İnce-Navigation Systems Engineer at Airbus Defence and Space talha.ince@airbus.com

Hobbies

Playing computer games, Salsa, Bachata, guitar, table tennis, doing workout, singing and writing songs, swimming.

